Finding aid to the Celebration records CA.MS.00326
Smith College Archives
Celebration records
1991-2010
Smith College Archives
Celebration
CA.MS.00326
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Celebration started in 1991 as an annual Celebration of Sisterhood, focusing on celebrating lesbian and bisexual culture. Contains correspondence, agendas, programs, news articles, and photos.
Biographical / Historical
The Celebration of Sisterhood began in 1991 as a Quad Vigil in order for the Smith campus and Pioneer Valley community to celebrate lesbian and bisexual connections and culture. The Celebration of Sisterhood was eventually shortened to Celebration, in order for the event to be more inclusive of trans-identified persons. Celebration was prompted to begin after a serious of homophobic incidents on campus, and turned into an annual event. Held on the Wilson House Steps, Celebration generally begins with a candlelight vigil, followed by various performances by Smith sports teams, quad houses, and a cappella groups.
Scope and Contents
The Celebration records contain a charter, correspondence, news articles, budget information, flyers, posters, programs, notes, calendar, and photos.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Celebration papers were donated to the Smith College Archives from a number of sources.
- Charter, undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 1)
- History, 1991-2006 (Box 3003.1, Folder 2)
- Advertising, 1995-2007 (Box 3003.1, Folder 3)
- Agendas, 2004-2008 (Box 3003.1, Folder 4)
- Audio and lighting, 2000-2002 (Box 3003.1, Folder 5)
- Budget and finances, 2002-2007; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 6)
- Campus Center organization and event information, 2006 (Box 3003.1, Folder 7)
- Clippings, 1991-1997; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1991; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 9)
- House skits and tables, 1994-1995; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 10)
- Interview forms for Celebration committee, 2006-2007 (Box 3003.1, Folder 11)
- Opening remarks for event (notes), 2006; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 12)
- Posters, 1996-2010; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 13)
- Programs, 1993-2010 (Box 3003.1, Folder 14)
- Protests (anti-Celebration propaganda), 2001 (Box 3003.1, Folder 15)
- To-do lists and planning, 1999-2006; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 16)
- Transgender issues, 2002; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 17)
- T-shirts, 1992-2007; undated (Box 3003.1, Folder 18)
- Photographs, 1993-1995 (Box 3003.1, Folder 19)